agile - the ability to  ant, science, respond in efficient and effective ways; which lowers the cost of change an uncertainty
discover, design, develop, test
agile is based on iterative and incremental development

srcum is a lightweight approach
scaled agile framework is a more robust approach

agile values: 
	1. individuals and interactions
	2. working deliverables
	3. customer collaboration
	4. responding to change
agile principles:
	1. satisfy the customer through early 
2. Respond and adapt to changing business needs
3. Working products/systems/solutions
agile fundamentals:
	1. iterative and incremental
	2. empiricism
	3. collective responsibility
	4. customer centricity
	5. decentralized decision making
leadership: respect for ppl and culture, flow, innovation, and relentless improvement
	test first, pair work, automate, design simply
po -> scrum -> delivery team

work comes form exploration, ideation, and collaboration
INVEST 
	Independent
	Negotiable
	Valuable
	Estimable
	Small
	Testable
definition of done: a) completion of automated unit testing b) ensuring performance standards have been met d) necessary documentation or user guides are up to date

user story analysisL 1)effort 2)complexity 3) lvl of doubt
velocity measures the rate of work acceptance over time 
	- is calculated by counting the total # of story points to user stories accepted by the PO w/in the timebox
productivity, efficiency, sustainability, predictability
agile scrum events: have focused outcomes, succinct, team participation
Cadence, Capacity, Commitment, Change, Culture, Check, Quality
slice features: 
	choose simplest implementation	
	defer options
	deliver incremental use cases
	isolate common reusable enables
	80/20 rule
	breakout investigation

starfish retrospective
REST: representational state transfer
URN: uniform resrouce name
URL: uniform resource locator
URI: string of chars that ident a resource

HTTP methods:
	Get
	Head: status line and header
	Post: posts data to the server
	Put: update the resource
	Delete: delete the resource
	Trace
	Options: returns http methods
	Connect: establishes a connection to the larger server
	Patch: partial mods
1xx: informational
2xx: success
3xx: redirection
4xx: client errors
5xx: server errors

Architectural constraints of rest: uniform interface, stateless, cacheable, client server, layered system, code on demand

richardson maturity lvl: 
	Lvl 0: http as transport
	Lvl 1: resources
	Lvl 2: http verbs
	Lvl 3: Hyper media
API (Application Programming Interface): a software program that allows two applications to communicate w/ eo

programming languages for web services: java, python, javascript, node.js
ipsec: helps protect data as it moves from its source to its destination
authorization: verifies that the connection attempt is allowed
